为了展示出
In order to show you how
一个大型交响乐团是怎么组成的
a big symphony
orchestra is put together,
Benjamin Britten创作了一长段
Benjamin Britten
has written a big piece of music,
由小的片段组成的乐章
which is made up
of smaller pieces
向你展示交响乐团的组成部分
that show you all
the separate parts of the orchestra.
这些小的片段就叫变奏曲
These smaller pieces
are called variations,
意思就是用不同的方法演奏同样的旋律
which means different ways
of playing the same tune.
他首先让我们听曲调或者主旋律
First of all,
he lets us hear the tune or the theme,
这是一段由年长的多的英国作曲家Henry Purcell
which is a beautiful melody
创作的美妙旋律
by the much older
British composer Henry Purcell.
现在听到的就是整个乐团一起演奏的主旋律
Here is Purcell's theme
played by the whole orchestra together.
现在Britten先生会让你听到乐团中四个不同的部
Now, Mr. Britten lets you hear
the four different families of the orchestra
用不同的方式演奏同一段主旋律
playing the same Purcell theme
in different ways.
我们首先听到的是木管乐器部
First, we hear
the woodwind family.
长笛，双簧管，单簧管和低音管
The ?utes, the oboes,
the clarinets and the bassoons.
现在是铜管乐器部
Here comes the brass family.
小号，号，长号和大号
The trumpets, the horns,
the trombones and the tubas.
一比四
One to four.
现在Britten先生让弦乐部来演奏主旋律
Now, Mr. Britten arranges the Purcell theme
for the string family.
我烦死这雨了
I'm sick of this rain.
小提琴，中提琴，大提琴和低音提琴
The violins,
the violas, the cellos and the double basses.
当然了，还有竖琴
And of course, the harp.
最后是打击乐部
And finally
the percussion family,
鼓，锣，还有你敲的东西
all those drums and gongs
and things you hit.
之后，你会听到所有四个部一起
After this, you will
hear the theme by Purcell
按主旋律原来的形式再演奏一遍
played once more in its original
form by all four families together.
这就是整个交响乐团
That is, the whole orchestra.
这就是新潘赞斯岛
This is
the island of New Penzance.
16英里长
16 miles long.
满布老松树和枫树
Forested with
old-growth pine and maple.
浅溪流在其间交错
Criss-crossed by
shallow tidal creeks.
Chickchaw聚居区
Chickchaw territory.
没有公路，但是……
There are no
paved roads, but...
送信的来了
Here comes Jed
with the mail.
但是有长长的交错的足迹和土路
But instead many
miles of intersecting footpaths and dirt trails,
还有从石洞每天往返两次的渡轮
and a ferry that
runs twice daily from Stone Cove.
现在是1965年
The year is 1965.
我们在Black Beacon Sound的远端
We are on the far edge
of Black Beacon Sound,
这地方因为有记录在案的猛烈风暴而出了名
famous for the ferocious
and well-documented storm,
风暴会在9月5日从东部袭击而来
which will
strike from the east on the 5th of September.
就是三天之后
In three days' time.
早，小子
Morning, Gadge.
早，先生
Morning, sir.
Deluca，检查厕所
Deluca,
latrine inspection.
好
Good.
Roosevelt，系绳弄得怎么样？
Roosevelt,
how's that lanyard coming?
太烂了
Horrible.
Skotak，这些木材是干嘛用的？
Skotak,
what's all this lumber for?
我们在搭树屋
We're building a tree house.
- 在哪？
- 就在这
- Where?
- Right here.
这个高度不安全。弄这么高干什么？
That's not a safe altitude.
Why is it up so high?
要是有人摔下去，就死定了
If someone falls from there,
that's a guaranteed death.
那要是你的话，你建在哪？
Well, where would
you have built it?
低一点的地方
Lower.
Nickleby？你干嘛呢？
Nickleby?
What are you doing?
防控害虫。我在烧蚂蚁
Pest control.
Burning some ants.
抽查啦
Spot check.
袜子没提起来，衬衫没掖进去
Your socks are down,
your shirt tails are untucked,
裤子也没扣好
your trousers are
not properly pressed.
记你制服违规
You are reported for
a uniform violation.
Panagle，你做了多少火箭？
How many rockets
you up to, Panagle?
十六个半，先生
Sixteen and a half, sir.
够叛乱用了没有？
Is that enough
for the Hullabaloo?
Izod，去军火库再拿一品脱火药
Izod, go fetch another pint of
gunpowder from the armory shed.
Redford！停下！我看见了！
Redford! Halt!
I saw that!
- 你刚刚开多快？
- 我这是为了安全检测，先生
- How fast were you just going?
- Safety test, sir.
再来一遍？
Come again?
这车看起来运转良好
The vehicle
appears to be in good working order,
我就是想检验一下……
I'm just checking if...
鲁莽驾驶，第二次警告
Reckless cycling.
Second warning.
你再这样，我就没收钥匙
Next time,
I take away the keys.
早上好，大厨
Morning, Chef.
肃静！
Clear!
少谁？
Who's missing?
- 少谁？
- 沙考斯基
- Who's missing?
- Shakusky.
- 沙考斯基
沙考斯基！吃早饭啦！
Shakusky! Breakfast!
沙考斯基，人呢？
Shakusky, you in there?
萨姆？
Sam?
是从里面拉上的
It's zipped from the inside.
我的天，他逃了
（肖申克又被黑了-_-）
Jiminy Cricket,
he flew the coop.
你好，我是夏普警长，完毕
Hello, this is
Captain Sharp, over.
夏普警长，我是兰道 沃德，在Ivanhoe营，完毕
Captain Sharp, this is Randall
Ward over at Camp Ivanhoe. Over.
早上好，兰迪，我能帮你什么？完毕
Morning, Randy.
What can I do for you? Over.
我还不确定。我这有个童子军逃跑了。完毕
I'm not sure exactly.
I've got an escaped Khaki Scout. Over.
什么意思？完毕
What does that mean? Over.
我这有个小男孩，好像是偷走了
One of my boys
seems to have stolen
一条小船和一些渔具
a miniature canoe and
some fishing tackle,
10磅杂货，两个铺盖卷还有一把气步枪
10 pounds of sundries,
two bedrolls, plus an air ri?e.
然后失踪了。完毕
And disappeared. Over.
知道为什么吗？完毕
Any idea why? Over.
不知道。他留给我一封辞职信。完毕
No. He left me
a letter of resignation. Over.
亲爱的沃德童子军长
Dear Scout Master Ward,
我遗憾地告知您，我没法呆在
I am very sad to inform you
I can no longer be involved
北美童子军中
with the Khaki
Scouts of North America.
余下部队应该很高兴听到这个消息
The rest of the troop
will probably be glad to hear this.
这不是你的错
It is not your fault.
祝好
萨姆 沙考斯基
Best wishes, Sam Shakusky.
呃，我觉得我们还是通知他家人吧，完毕
Well, I guess we better
notify his folks. Over.
好，完毕，结束通话
Okay. Over and out.
你好，戴安
Hello, Diane.
贝琪，从Chesterfield的电话
Becky, I have your
person-to-person from Chesterfield
别挂
Hold the line, please.
喂？
Hello?
你好，先生 我是夏普警长
Hello, sir.
This is Captain Sharp.
是，先生，我收到你的消息了，非常感谢
Yes, sir. I received your
message. Thank you very much.
我们以家庭名义做出了决定
In fact, we've come to
a decision, as a family,
因为在萨姆闹出的这么多乱子当中这才只是最近的一个意外
because this is only the most recent
incident involving Sam's troubles,
而且对其他人也不公平，所以，很遗憾
and it's just not
fair to the others, so, unfortunately,
这个时候我们不能让他回来
we can't invite him
back at this time.
不是警告，先生。我们会找到他的
There's no cause
for alarm, sir. We'll find him.
我们只是礼节性地通知您
We're simply notifying you
as a matter of protocol and so on.
我明白，我是告诉您我这边的情况
I understand that.
I'm notifying you of the situation on my end.
你这么就把我说糊涂了。你不能把他带回来？
I'm confused by
that statement. You can't invite him back?
恐怕不行。他是个好孩子，心地很好
I'm afraid not.
He's a good boy. He's got a good heart.
但这样对其他人不公平，明白吗？
But it's just not fair
to the others, you see?
他情绪混乱
He's emotionally disturbed.
您是萨姆的父亲吗？
Am I speaking
with Sam's father?
不是，先生
No, sir.
萨姆的父母几年前去世了
Sam's parents passed away
a number of years ago.
我们是比林斯利夫妇，养父母
We're Mr. and
Mrs. Billingsley. We're foster parents.
从去年六月萨姆就在我们家住
Sam's been with
us since last June.
打扰了，先生 我是童子军长沃德
Excuse me, sir.
This is Scout Master Ward speaking.
你是说萨姆是个孤儿？
Are you implying
that Sam is an orphan?
嗯，这是事实。当然。
Well, it's a known fact.
Of course he is.
那他登记的时候怎么不他妈的说清楚？
Well, why the hell
doesn't it say so in the register?
抱歉我说脏话了
Excuse my language.
我不清楚 什么登记？
I don't know.
What register?
我们给他寄了封信，现在你们应该收到了
We sent him a letter.
It should reach you presently.
比林斯利先生，有个童子军失踪了
Mr. Billingsley,
I've got an escaped Khaki Scout.
我们礼节性地通知您
We are notifying you
as a matter of protocol.
你说你不能让他回来？他是孤儿？
You say you can't
invite him back? You say that he's an orphan?
我不懂这是怎么回事
I don't understand
how that works.
那我拿他怎么办？
What am I supposed
to do with him?
这就是社工的事了，他们会联系你的
That's up to social services.
They'll be in touch with you.
他们会照顾萨姆的，祝你好运
They'll look after Sam.
Good luck to you.
听好指令
You have your orders.
用追踪和寻找足迹的方法
Use the orienteering
and path-finding skills
你们都练了一个夏天了
that you've been
practicing all summer.
找到我们的人，把他安全带回营里
Let's find our man,
bring him safely back to camp.
记住了，这可不是什么寻宝
Remember, this isn't
just a search party,
是当一级童子军的机会
it's a chance to do
some first class Scouting.
有问题么？
Any questions?
瞌睡虫？
Lazy-Eye?
你真正的工作是什么，先生？
What's your real job, sir?
- 我是数学老师。问这个干什么？
- 教几年级？
- I'm a math teacher. Why?
- What grade?
- 初二
- 你要拿博士学位么？
- Eighth.
- You need a PhD for that?
不用，瞌睡虫，但是你注意了
Lazy-Eye, no,
but you know what,
我们现在在干正事
we're actually in the middle of something
here, in case you didn't notice.
我们中间有人失踪了，很危险
One of our Scouts is missing
and that's a crisis.
还有人有问题吗？Redford？
Anybody else?
Redford?
他要是拒捕怎么办？
What if he resists?
- 谁？
- 沙考斯基
- Who?
- Shakusky.
我们能对他采取强制措施么？
Are we allowed to
use force on him?
不行。这是非暴力营救行动
No, you're not.
This is a non-violent, rescue operation.
你的任务就是找到他，无论如何也不能伤害他
Your mission is to find him,
not to hurt him under any circumstances.
懂了没？
Am I making
myself understood?
- 是
- 很好
- Yes.
- Good.
我要重新回答一下，现在这就是我真实的工作
I'm going to change my answer,
in fact, this is my real job.
童子军55营长。除此之外我是个教数学的
Scout Master Troop 55.
I'm a math teacher on the side.
机灵点。好不好？
Be leery out there. Okay?
现在开始吧。谁看见史努比了？
Now let's get started.
Who's got Snoopy?
在这
Right here.
让他闻一闻
Give him the scent.
我听说他逃跑是因为他父母死了
I heard he ran away
because his family died.
我听说他从来没有家
I heard he
never had any family in the first place.
估计就因为这个他才不正常
That's probably
why he's crazy.
告诉你们
I'll tell you one thing,
如果咱们找到他了，我可不要成为那个忘了带武器的
if we find him, I'm not going to be the
one who forgot to bring a weapon.
我也不要
Me, neither.
Ivanhoe营，那可是在岛的另一边
Camp Ivanhoe, that's all the way
across the other side of the island.
你真的觉得一个12岁小孩
You really think
a 12-year-old boy
用这么小的船能划那么远？
could row this far
in a miniature canoe?
不太可能
Most likely not.
有这个可能，管理员
It is possible, Counselor.
我不同意，管理员。他得至少划上三天
I disagree, Counselor.
It would take him three days, at least.
我不同意。两天最多了
I don't think so.
Two days, maximum.
- 我不和你争这个了
- 不管这个了
- Well, I'm not going to argue about it.
- Be that as it may,
- 你发现什么异常情况就告诉我，好吗？
- 好
- will you let me know if you see anything unusual?
- Yup.
童子军长日志，9月2日
Scout Master's log,
September 2nd.
寻找萨姆 沙考斯基第一天
First day of search
party for Sam Shakusky
士气低迷
Morale is extremely low,
我觉得也许是
in part, I suppose,
因为萨姆是最不受欢迎的一个童子军
because Sam is
the least popular Scout in the troop.
他比其他人都不受欢迎的多
By a significant margin.
我困惑又着急
I'm confused
and I'm worried.
保佑我们明天能找到他吧
Please let us
find him tomorrow.
不要让他摔下悬崖
Please don't let
him fall off a cliff,
淹死在哪个倒霉湖里什么的
or drown in the goddamn
lake or something.
Ivanhoe营糟糕的一天
A terrible day
at Camp Ivanhoe.
希望明天能变更好
Let's hope
tomorrow's better.
一年前
One Year earlier
你是什么鸟？
What kind of bird are you?
我是麻雀，她是鸽子
I'm a sparrow,
she's a dove...
不是，我是说，你是哪种鸟？
No. I said,
what kind of bird are you?
我是渡鸦
I'm a raven.
男生不许进来
Boys aren't
allowed in here.
我马上就走
I'll be leaving soon.
你的手怎么了？
What happened to your hand?
砸镜子砸的
I got hit in the mirror.
真的？怎么弄的？
Really, how did that happen?
我发脾气了
I lost my temper at myself.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
萨姆。你呢？
Sam. What's yours?
苏西
I'm Suzy.
瞪着人不礼貌
It's not polite to stare.
鸟儿们，准备好了吗？你是谁？
Birds, ready?
Who are you?
从哪冒出来的？回座位上去
Where did you come from?
Go back to your seat.
他喜欢你哎
He likes you.
你被跟踪了没？
Were you followed?
- 应该没有
- 很好
- I doubt it.
- Good.
那里面是只猫吗？
Is that a cat in there?
- 你会看地图吗？
- 嗯哼
- Can you read a map?
- Uh-huh.
我画了地图
I do cartography.
我觉得我们应该今天走到半路，明天走另一半
I feel we should
go halfway today, and halfway tomorrow
因为你没什么远足经验
since you're a less
experienced hiker,
你还穿着周末学校的鞋子
and you're wearing
Sunday school shoes.
这不是周末学校的鞋子
They're not really
Sunday school shoes.
给
Here.
哦，谢谢
Oh, thank you.
我们现在在这
Here's where
we are right now.
我想16点前在这扎营
I'd like to pitch
camp here by 1600,
就是四点。怎么样？
which means 4:00.
How does that sound?
- 好
- 想要点牛肉干么？
- Fine.
- You want some beef jerky?
- 好
- 走吧
- Okay.
- Let's go.
渴不渴？
Are you thirsty?
不，谢谢
No, thank you.
如果你口干舌燥
Well, if your throat
gets parched,
就在嘴里放块鹅卵石，然后吸它
stick a pebble in your
mouth and suck on it.
用口水就能解渴了，应该是这样
You can quench your thirst
with the spit, supposedly.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
有时候我在头上粘叶子，能让你的头降温
Sometimes I stick leaves on my
hair. It helps cool your head down.
嗯，是个好主意
Hmm. That's a good idea.
如果你没戴皮毛帽子，这样也能取暖
It might also help if
you didn't wear a fur hat.
对
Yeah. True.
你可以走了，小心
You can go ahead.
Be careful.
有个小窍门，往天上扔松枝
Here's a trick,
throw pine needles in the air
你就能看见风往哪边吹
and you can see
which direction the wind is blowing.
哪边走？
Which Way?
我觉得不要紧
I guess it
doesn't really matter,
只要我们能把足迹掩盖掉
just as long as we
cover our tracks.
你闻起来有香水味
You smell like perfume.
哦，是我妈妈的
Oh, it's my mother's.
嗯 嗯
Hmm. Hmm.
我带水了
I brought water, too.
- 你在这等
- 好
- You wait here.
- Okay.
我马上就回
Be right back.
小心头顶
Watch your head!
这是什么玩意？
Where the hell is it?
找到了！
Found it!
好了
It's ready.
他知道有人在看他
He knows someone's
watching him.
同意。等等，你为什么这么说
I agree. Wait.
Why do you say that?
嗯……不知道，我就是觉得他能感觉到我们的存在
Mmm... I don't know,
I just think he can feel us.
跟我走
Follow me.
你游泳有多好？
How strong of
a swimmer are you?
很好。我破了我们学校的仰泳纪录呢
Pretty good.
I broke our school record for the backstroke.
好吧，嗯，我游泳没那么好，所以我穿救生衣
Okay. Well, I'm not that strong of a
swimmer, so I wear a life preserver.
小心有乌龟
Watch out for turtles.
如果你把手放进它们嘴里，它们就会咬你的
They'll bite you
if you put your fingers down their mouths.
好吧
Okay.
让我看看能不能抓住这只
Let me see if I
can catch this one.
感觉到了
Feel something.
嗯
Hmm...
有人在它身上写字了
Somebody wrote on him.
鱼竿动了
The stick's moving.
钓到了！
You got one!
上钩啦！把线卷回来，慢一点
Fish on hook!
Reel him in, slowly.
嗯
Mmm.
很好吃。你很懂露营，对不对？
Very good.
You know a lot about camping, don't you?
我是个受过训练的童子军。呃，是这样，我以前是
I'm a Khaki Scout. It's what I'm trained
for. Well, anyway, I used to be.
可以把内脏和眼球拿来喂猫
Maybe we can feed your cat
the guts and eyeballs.
哦，不用了 他只吃猫粮
Oh, that's okay.
He only eats kitten food.
哦
Oh.
你还带了什么？没准我们可以做点什么出来
What else did you bring?
Maybe we can make an inventory.
好
Okay.
来吧
Go ahead.
这是我的唱机，放上电池才能用
This is my record player.
It works with batteries.
呃，实际上，是我弟弟莱昂内尔的
Well, actually,
it belongs to my little brother, Lionel.
- 我给他留了张条
- 好的
- I left him a note.
- Okay.
- 你喜欢音乐？
- 嗯
- Do you like music?
- Yeah.
这是我最喜欢的唱片
This is my
favorite record album.
我教母给我的生日礼物
My godmother gave it
to me for my birthday.
她住在法国
She lives in France.
这些是我的书，我喜欢有魔力的故事
These are my books.
I like stories with magic powers in them.
地球上的王国，或者外星上的
Either in kingdoms on Earth
or on foreign planets.
我喜欢女英雄的故事，但不总是这样
Usually, I prefer
a girl hero, but not always.
我没法把书都带着，太沉了
I couldn't bring them all
because it got too heavy.
你要是想要，可以借给你
You can borrow any you want.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还带了左撇子剪刀，因为我是个左撇子
I also brought
my lefty scissors because I'm left-handed,
皮筋，备用电池，牙刷
some rubber bands,
extra batteries, my toothbrush,
还有，望远镜，你看见了
and my binoculars,
as you know.
嗯
Yeah.
我忘带梳子了，但是用手就行
I forgot my comb.
But I'll use my fingers.
嗯
Huh.
等等，这些可都是图书馆的书
Wait, these are all
library books.
在我们学校，一次只能借一本
In my school, you're only
allowed to check out one at a time.
有些都要到期了
Some of these are
going to be overdue.
你偷的？
Do you steal?
为什么？你又不穷
Why? You're not poor.
我可能某一天会还一部分，我还不确定呢
I might turn some of
them back in one day. I haven't decided yet.
我知道这样不好。我觉得我偷书只是为了有秘密
I know it's bad. I think I just took
them to have a secret to keep.
不管怎样，出于某种原因
Anyway,
for some reason,
有时候这样能让我心情更好
it makes me feel in
a better mood sometimes.
你抑郁？
Are you depressed?
怎么？
How come?
如果你愿意我可以给你举个例子
Well, I can show you
an example, if you'd like,
但我不太好受
but it doesn't make
me feel very good.
管他呢。这是我家冰箱上面发现的
（书：如何与问题儿童相处）
Anyway, I found this
on top of our refrigerator.
指的是你？
Does that mean you?
应该是
I think so.
你在笑？
Are you laughing?
这不好笑
It's not funny.
你还真懂怎么交朋友
You really know
how to make friends.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
哦，没事
Oh. It's okay.
我支持你
I'm on your side.
我知道
I know.
谢谢
Thank you.
哪本最好？
Which one's the best?
他眼睛低垂，他的王国成为废墟，Mynar把他沉重的爪子
"His eyes downcast, his kingdom in
ruins, Mynar pressed his heavy paw
伸过浅滩波动的表面
"through the rippling surface
of the cool shallows
触到石质的河床
"and down to its stone floor.
我的人民曾经被伟大而高贵的野兽领导着
"My people once were led
by a great and noble beast
而我在这倒影里再也看不到他的样子
"and I no longer
see his face in this reflection.'
与此同时，Francine栖息在Tabitha的平原上
"Meanwhile,
on the Plains of Tabitha, Francine rested.
还会有另一次战争的
"There would be
another time for war."
苏西，吃饭啦！叫你最后一遍！
Suzy! Dinner! I'm not
going to say it again.
你们姐姐呢？
Where's your sister?
不知道，但是她连问都没问就借我唱机10天
I don't know, but she borrowed
my record player for 10 days without asking.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
亲爱的莱昂内尔，我需要用你的唱机
Dear Lionel, I need
to use your record player.
我十天之内还给你，不要告诉妈妈爸爸
I will give it back
in 10 days or less. Do not tell Mom. Or Dad.
我换了电池还给你。签名，苏西 毕肖普
I will replace the batteries when I
return. Signed, Suzy Bishop.
沃特！你跑哪去了！
Walt! Where the hell are you?
在这呢
Right here!
你冲我喊什么？
Why are you cursing at me?
你女儿离家出走了你都不管？
Does it concern you that
your daughter's just run away from home?
你怎么知道她离家出走了
That's a loaded question.
下来看这个
Come down and read this.
童子军长沃德确定，他们没有运气
Scout Master Ward
confirms they've had no luck.
他们就会回家……
They're going home for...
那是谁？
Who's there?
晚上好，抱歉吓你一跳
Good evening.
Sorry to startle you.
你在这干嘛？没人报警
What are you doing here?
Nobody called the police.
我知道 呃……
我知道
I know. Uh...
I know.
搜寻活动还没结束。换句话说
The search party's
not over yet. In other words...
苏西也丢了！快去找
Suzy's missing, too!
Go find her.
上周在英属洪都拉斯海岸形成的
The tropical cyclone,
which originated last week
热带气旋急速增强
off the coast of
British Honduras, has intensified rapidly
成为Mabeline飓风
and is now designated
Hurricane Mabeline.
请持续关注后续报道
Stay tuned for
further information
我们怎么帮她？她有那么多麻烦
How can we help her?
She's got so many problems.
更糟了
It's getting worse.
是谁的错？
Whose fault is it?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是，记录在案的是，95%的离家出走的人在六个小时之内
But just for the record
95 % of all runaways
就都跑回了家
return home within
the first six hours.
这些现在都没用。只是统计数字
That doesn't do you
any good right now. It's just a statistic.
但也有可能，苏西没准藏在她最好朋友家
But in all likelihood,
Suzy's probably hiding in the closet
的衣柜里玩中国象棋呢
at her best friend's house
playing Chinese checkers
就现在我们说话这会儿
at this very moment,
as we speak.
她没有一个朋友
She doesn't have any friends.
劳拉怎么样？
How's Laura?
什么“劳拉怎么样”
"How's Laura?"
毕肖普太太，我是说
Mrs. Bishop, I mean.
我不懂
I don't understand.
她很失落？
Is she upset?
有只豪猪
There's a porcupine.
她有个笔友！很私密，他们一起计划逃跑的
She has a pen pal!
It's very intimate. They planned this together.
萨姆 沙考斯基
那是我那逃跑的童子军
Sam Shakusky.
That's my escaped Khaki Scout.
他家人都死了
His family died.
我的天哪，这是什么
Holy Christ,
what am I looking at?
他画水彩。大部分是风景，也有几张裸体
He does watercolors.
Mostly landscapes, but a few nudes.
这画的是她？
She sit for this?
他说什么了？
What's he say?
亲爱的苏西，你的声音太美了
Dear Suzy,
you have a superb voice.
你是我在这个节目里到目前为止最喜欢的动物
You were my favorite animal
in the program, by far.
你在信封里找……
Please find enclosed...
亲爱的萨姆
非常感谢
Dear Sam,
thank you very much.
因为我冲着林恩太太大喊，我换成了渡鸦
I got replaced as the raven
because I yelled at Mrs. Lynn.
在那之后，我只是只蓝鸟
After that,
I was only a blue jay, but...
亲爱的苏西，很遗憾你的弟弟们这么自私
Dear Suzy, I'm sorry
that your brothers are so selfish.
也许长大了就不这样了
Maybe they will
grow out of it.
有时候人们会无意识地做出……
Sometimes people do things
without knowing the reasons for...
亲爱的萨姆，你是个优秀的画家
Dear Sam, you are
an excellent painter,
尤其是画树和电线杆
especially trees
and telephone poles.
水里的女孩是我吗？我最喜欢的颜色……
Is the girl in the water supposed to be
me? My favorite color is...
亲爱的苏西，我梦游的时候不小心点着了火
Dear Suzy, I accidentally built a
fire while I was sleepwalking.
我记不清了，但是我养父母说我骗人
I have no memory of this,
but my foster parents think I am lying.
不幸的是……
Unfortunately, it is...
亲爱的萨姆，我又惹麻烦了
Dear Sam,
I am in trouble again
因为我冲着窗户扔石头
because I threw a rock
through the window.
我妈妈到现在头发里还有玻璃，还有……
My mother still has
glass in her hair. Also...
亲爱的苏西，我有非常努力地交朋友
Dear Suzy, I have been
trying very hard to make friends,
但我觉得别人不喜欢我的性格
but I feel people do
not like my personality.
其实我能理解他们为什么不……
In fact, I can understand
why they might not...
亲爱的萨姆，现在我被停学了
Dear Sam,
now I am getting suspended
因为我和莫莉打了一架
because I got in
a fight with Molly.
她说我是个疯子，我们校长也不向着我。为什么有人……
She says I go berserk.
Our principal is against me. Why do some...
亲爱的苏西，我知道你父母伤害了你的感情
Dear Suzy, I know your parents
hurt' your feelings,
但他们还是爱你的。这个更重要。如果他们……
but they still love you.
That is more important. If they...
亲爱的萨姆
我觉得你确实应该
Dear Sam,
I do think you should
每天想起他们的脸
think of their
faces every day,
就算是这样会让你很伤心
even if it makes you sad.
好遗憾他们没有留给你
It is too bad they
did not leave you
更多他们的画。你能不能……
more pictures of themselves.
Can you...
亲爱的苏西，这是我的计划
Dear Suzy, here is my plan.
亲爱的萨姆，我同意
Dear Sam, my answer is yes.
亲爱的苏西，什么时候？
Dear Suzy, when?
亲爱的萨姆，在哪？
Dear Sam, where?
亲爱的苏西，从你家往北走400码
Dear Suzy,
walk 400 yards due north from your house
走到那条没名的土路
to the dirt path
which has not got any name on it.
右拐走到头。我在草地和你会合
Turn right and follow to the
end. I will meet you in the meadow.
天，你觉得他会怎么样？
Gee whiz, what do you
suppose happened to him?
我不知道，他应该是天黑的时候出去找人了
I'm not sure.
I think he went searching in the dark.
她把我手电筒里的电池都偷了
She stole the batteries
out of my flashlight.
偷手电筒里的电池……
Stole the batteries
out of the flashlight...
我觉得他是冲着我们来的
I think he's onto us.
当然了
Of course he is.
当然了？
Of course he is?
当然了
Of course he is.
那为什么我们不担心？
Then why aren't we
worried about that?
我担心着呢
I am.
我不知道了
Well, I didn't know.
或者，我觉得我搞错了
Or, anyway,
I thought maybe I was wrong.
你打他了？
Did you hit him?
没有，他摔进沟里了
No. He fell in a ditch.
嘿！有猫粮！我觉得这是线索
Hey! Cat food!
I think it's a clue.
那是她的
That's her.
他要去哪
Where's he going?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧，我们知道了他俩是在一起的
All right,
we know they're together.
我们知道了他俩就在这方圆不远距离内
We know they're within
a certain radius of this spot.
我要向县里报案
I'm declaring a case
with the county right now.
到有人来帮忙之前，我任命这个小孩，瘦的这个
Until help arrives,
I'm deputizing the little guy, the skinny one,
还有蒙眼的这个小孩
and the boy with
the patch on his eye
和我到警车里来
to come with me in
the station wagon.
兰迪，你顺便和余下部队去河边
Randy, you drop in and head up
river with the rest of your troops,
分头步行
split up on foot.
贝琪，你叫杰德绕着
Becky, call Jed,
tell him to circle over
岛的这一头低飞
this end of the island
and fly low.
这是他们？
Is it them?
是，是
Yeah, yeah.
他们找到了营火
They found the campfire.
老鼠！我应该多放些松针的。走吧
Rats! I should have put
more pine needles on it. Let's go.
小心
Be careful.
你们这些疯子想干嘛？
What do you creeps want?
我们在找你
We're looking for you.
为什么？
Why?
嗯，因为你逃跑了
Well, because
you're a fugitive.
没有。我退出童子军了
No, I'm not.
I quit the Khaki Scouts.
那也没用。你没那个权力
Well, it doesn't matter
anyway. You don't have that authority.
我们被任命来找你
We've been deputized.
你是服服帖帖跟我们走，还是要怎样？
Now, you're going to come
along peacefully or not?
听我说理由
Listen to some reason.
我不喜欢你们，你们也不喜欢我
I don't like you.
You don't like me.
那你们为什么不干脆让我们消失？
So, why don't you
just let us disappear?
嗯，很有诱惑力，但是我们不准这样
Well, it's tempting,
but we can't allow it.
你知道，你不应该和他交朋友
You know,
you shouldn't be friends with him.
为什么？
Why not?
因为他是个疯子
Because he's crazy.
你可能只是不了解他
Maybe you just
don't know him.
实际上我们比你了解得多
Actually, we know him
a lot better than you.
他情绪紊乱，因为他家人都死了
He's emotionally disturbed
because his family died.
Nickelby，把他绑起来
Nickleby, tie him up.
你敢越过这根树枝一步
Do not cross this stick.
你死定了，沙考斯基
You're doomed, Shakusky.
莫莉说得对，我是疯了
Molly's right,
I do go berserk.
还好是他，不然我们就死定了
It was him or us.
哦，不
Oh, no.
她用左撇子剪刀戳了Redford的后背
She stabbed
Redford in the back with lefty scissors.
请再说一遍 完毕
Repeat that, please? Over.
他受了刺伤，在腰下面
在机舱里挪点地方放担架
Puncture wound, lower lumbar.
Make room for a stretcher in the cockpit.
你会没事的
You're going to be okay.
谢天谢地她没戳中动脉。咬着这个
Thank goodness she
missed the artery. Here, bite on this.
我想砍他的，但是他躲开了我的斧头
I tried to chop him,
but he dodged my tomahawk.
他枪法太好了
He's got
excellent marksmanship.
把Deluca两条胳膊都打中了
Shot Deluca in both arms.
我觉得我们要错过叛乱了
I guess we're going to miss
the Hullabaloo after all.
史努比呢？
Where's Snoopy?
这些混蛋
Those sons of bitches.
他们打穿了他的脖子
They got him right
through the neck.
他是条好狗吗
Was he a good dog?
谁知道呢。但他不该死
Who's to say.
But he didn't deserve to die.
怎么了？那是谁？
What happened?
Who is that?
把码头清开，埃德加
Clear the dock, Edgar!
- 他怎么流血了？
- 苏西和你在一起吗？
- Why is he bleeding?
- Is Suzy with you?
不，她和沙考斯基在树林里
No, she's in
the woods with Shakusky.
我要去哪？
Where am I going?
黎巴嫩堡的治疗室。我们就在你后面。知道了吗？
The infirmary at Fort Lebanon.
We'll be right behind you. You got it?
嗯
Yup.
发动机打上火，我马上就回
Warm up the motor,
I'll be right back.
不许动
Hold it right there!
你不许离开这座岛
You're not
leaving this island.
咱们的女儿被一个疯子童子军拐走了
Our daughter has been
abducted by one of these beige lunatics.
沃特，这很明显
Walt, it's very clear.
这两个人密谋私奔了
The two of them
conspired in this together.
别着急，毕肖普先生 她会没事的
Don't worry,
Mr. Bishop. She'll be safe.
萨姆很会伪装
Sam's got excellent
wilderness skills.
你怎么不管好你的童子军？
Why can't you
control your Scouts?
我很努力啊
Well, I'm trying.
哇 哇 嘿
Whoa, whoa. Hey.
停下 停下
Stop it! Stop it!
- 停下
- Stop it!
- Stop it.
我确实怪他。但是我也怪我自己和你们俩
I do blame him.
But I also blame myself and both of you.
恕我直言，你可不能让你孩子捅人
With all due respect,
you can't let your children stab people.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
她有暴力倾向，毕肖普太太，这是袭击
She's violent,
Mrs. Bishop, it's assault.
- 你是律师？
- 不我不是律师
- Are you a lawyer?
- No, I'm not a lawyer.
哈，我们可是！
Well, we are!
把你手从我老婆身上拿下来
Take your hands
off my wife!
放开她
Take them off!
抱歉，抱歉，夏普警长
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Captain Sharp!
你们有些人知道，我教萨姆
As some of you know,
I taught Sam
得到了绘地图技术的勋章
for the cartography
accomplishment button.
他是个聪明的孩子，表现出对
He's a smart boy
and he expressed a keen interest
岛上土著人历史的兴趣
in the history of the island's
indigenous peoples.
我还记得他对古Chickchaw人收获季迁徙
In particular,
I recall his fascination with the idea
的遗迹特别感兴趣
of retracing the original
path of the old Chickchaw harvest migration.
我是说，我知道他们会往哪走
What I'm getting at is this.
I think I know where they're going.
在鸟舍
Onto the birdhouse,
所有你能想象得到的鸟儿
where every kind
of bird imaginable
都在旋转的地方
is whirling
and wheeling around.
这是我们的地盘
This is our land!
是的
Yes, it is!
喔
Whoo!
跑啊
Run!
跳吧
Let's jump!
数到三
On three!
一，二，三
One, two, three!
你们有谁曾经很辛苦地练习钢琴的
Any of you who have ever
had to sweat through piano exercises
就会同情这些……
will sympathize with these...
我喜欢这里，但我不喜欢这个名字
I like it here,
but I don't like the name.
我也不喜欢
Me, neither.
3.25里潮汐湾
这也不是环形的
"Mile 3.25 Tidal Inlet"
It's got no ring to it.
换个名字吧
叫什么呢
Let's change it.
What should it be?
让我想一会
Let me think
for a minute.
我给你做了些首饰
I made you some jewelry.
你耳朵有洞么
Are your ears pierced?
很漂亮
It's pretty.
另一只也戴上
Do the other one.
为什么你总拿着望远镜？
Why do you
always use binoculars?
让我能更近地看东西，即使是不太远的东西也可以
It helps me see things
closer, even if they're not very far away.
我假装这是我的特异功能
I pretend it's
my magic power.
嗯
Hmm.
听着就像一首诗
That sounds like poetry.
诗歌不总是押韵的，你知道
Poems don't always
have to rhyme, you know.
就该有创造性
They're just
supposed to be creative.
那你长大了想干什么？
So, what do you want to be
when you grow up?
不知道，我想去冒险，我觉得
I don't know.
I want to go on adventures, I think.
不能总呆在一个地方。你呢？
Not get stuck in one place.
How about you?
我也想去冒险。我也不想呆在一个地方
Go on adventures, too.
Not get stuck, too.
但是我们没法预见未来
Anyway, we can't
predict the exact future.
是啊
That's true.
顺便说一句，我有可能尿床的，晚上，我是说
It's possible I may
wet the bed, by the way. Later, I mean.
没事
Okay.
我希望我不需要提起这事，但就是以防万一
I wish I didn't
have to mention it, but just in case.
我不想让你觉得被冒犯
I don't want to
make you be offended.
当然不会
Of course I won't.
那个是干吗用的？
What's that one for?
- 这个？
- 对
- This?
- Yeah.
这不是勋章
It's not
an accomplishment button.
我妈妈传给我的
I inherited it
from my mother.
不应该是男生戴的，但我才不管呢
It's not actually meant for a male to
wear, but I don't give a damn.
你养父母还因为你总惹麻烦
Are your foster parents
still mad at you,
而生你的气吗
for getting in
trouble so much?
不了
I don't think so.
我们开始更加了解对方了
We're starting to get to
know each other better.
我感觉到我在一个真正的家庭里
I feel I'm in
a real family now.
和你家不一样，但是差不多了
Not like yours,
but similar to one.
我总是希望自己是个孤儿
I always wished
I was an orphan.
我喜欢的角色大部分都是
Most of my
favorite characters are.
我觉得你的生活更特别
I think your lives
are more special.
我爱你，但是你不知道你在说什么
I love you, but you don't know
what you're talking about.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
- 我嘴里有沙子
- 哦
- I've got sand in my mouth.
- Oh.
呃……你会法式舌吻吗？
Uh... Can you French kiss?
应该会吧。有什么秘诀么？
I think so.
Is there any secret to it?
要碰到对方的舌头
The tongues touch each other.
好，试试看
Okay, let's try it.
感觉很硬
It feels hard.
你介意吗？
Do you mind?
我喜欢
I like it.
把你的头歪到一边
Tilt your head sideways.
你可以摸我的胸
You can touch my chest.
我……我觉得他们开始长了
I... I think they're
going to grow more.
手电筒的光束把月光从黑暗中引出来
"The flashlight's
beam drew a moon through the black
穿过阁楼，落在护壁板的缝隙中
"across the attic
and settled on a gap in the baseboard.
一个没有怀表大的老鼠洞
"A mouse hole,
no bigger than a pocket watch.
平足的埃里克蹲下来
"Eric crouched
on his flat feet
把他的手放在那细小的开口前面
"and placed his hand in
front of the tiny opening.
起风了，他说
"'It's windy,' he said.
就像有人在往我手上吹气
"'Like someone in there's
blowing on my fingers.'
克里斯蒂翻翻眼睛，叹了口气
"Christy rolled her
eyes and sighed a sigh.
他又说对了，她想
"'He's right again,'
she thought.
小男孩让人发疯
"'Little brothers
drive people crazy."'
我听着呢，继续念
I'm listening. Read on.
第二部分
Part two.
不！
No!
亲爱的萨姆，很伤心写这封信给你
Dear Sam, it saddens
me to write this letter,
但比林斯利太太和我决定
but Mrs. Billingsley
and I have decided
我们不能让你回我们家了
we cannot permit you
to return to our home.
我知道你本意是好的，但是相信我，这是为了你好
I know you mean well.
Do trust me, this is for the best.
祝好
赫伯特 比林斯利
Godspeed,
Herbert Billingsley.
听好了，你们俩再也不会见到对方了
Be advised, the two of you will
never see each other again.
这些就是临别赠言了 懂了没？
Those were your last words.
Do you understand?
如果我是你，我会小心
I'd be careful
if I were you.
这几天，有人走得太远了
One of these days,
somebody's going to get pushed too far,
谁知道他们能做什么
and who knows what
they're capable of.
这是在威胁吗？
Is that a threat?
这是在警告
It's a warning.
你是我们家的叛徒
You're a traitor
to our family.
真好。我倒想当叛徒呢
Good. I want to be.
我很抱歉 我不知道你的情况
I'm sorry about this.
I didn't know your situation.
你登记的时候没说
It wasn't in the register.
你父母是怎么死的？
How'd you lose your parents?
算了，我不需要问这个的
Never mind, I don't
need to ask about that.
我希望我们能有时间回去在海边巡查
I wish we had time
to do an inspection back there. On the beach.
我会表扬你的
I would have given
you a commendable.
你做的是我看到过的最好的营房之一了
That was one of the
best pitched campsites I've ever seen.
说真的
Honestly.
谢谢
Thank you
你不想再当童子军了吗？
You don't want to be
a Khaki Scout anymore?
喂，贝琪
Hello, Becky?
朱迪，从新潘赞斯打来的电话
Judy, I have your
person-to-person from New Penzance.
继续，新潘赞斯
Go ahead, New Penzance.
喂，我是夏普警长
Hello, this is
Captain Sharp.
你好，夏普警长 这里是社会服务部
Hello, Captain Sharp.
This is Social Services.
我打电话是问萨姆 沙考斯基的事，他是被监护人
I'm calling in
reference to Sam Shakusky, ward of the state.
我知道他现在在你的监护下
I understand he's
in your custody.
对
That's correct.
他情况怎样？他有受伤
What's his condition?
Has he suffered
或者遭到心理创伤吗？
any injury or
trauma of any kind?
- 他很好
- 很好
- He's fine.
- Very good.
我怎么去找你？
How do I get to you?
最快的方式是海上飞机
The fastest way
would be sea plane.
杰德可以把你和信一起送来
Jed can bring you
in with the mail.
如果你同意，我明早过来
I'll come tomorrow morning,
if that's acceptable to you.
有人能在这孩子成年之前
Is someone able to
provide reasonable care
好好看护和抚养他吗？
and nourishment for
the boy until that time?
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
你是在说是吗？
Is that a yes?
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
很好，我今天晚上之前会再联系你一次
Very good, I'll contact you
again before the end of the day.
等一下
Wait a second.
什么？
Yes?
社会服务？
Social Services?
夏普警长？
Captain Sharp?
他会怎么样？
What's going to
happen to him?
呃，正常情况下我们会给他再找一个寄养家庭
Well, normally,
we try to place him in another foster home,
但我觉得那种方式我们做不到
but that option's no
longer available to us,
从他的档案来看是这样的
in my opinion,
due to his case history.
也就是说，他会去少管所
Which means he'll go
to Juvenile Refuge.
等等。这是什么意思？孤儿院么？
Wait. What does that mean?
Is that an orphanage?
是谁？
Who's speaking?
我是童子军营长兰迪 沃德
This is Scout Master
Randy Ward.
对，是孤儿院
Right, an orphanage.
但第一步，收容小组
But the first step is
the admissions panel
需要对他进行心理评估
requires
a psychological evaluation
来确定这孩子是需要
to determine
whether or not the boy
专业医疗
is a candidate for
institutional treatment
还是电休克疗法
or electroshock therapy.
等等。休克疗法？
Excuse me.
Shock therapy?
为什么要对他来这个？他又没有攻击性。
Why would that
be called for? He's not violent.
报告中描述了他用剪刀袭击人
The report describes
an assault with scissors.
那是那女孩
That was the girl.
是那女孩干的
That was the girl
that did that.
也许那女孩也需要帮助，但这不是我们的责任，知道了吗？
Well, maybe she needs help,
too, but that's not our job. Okay?
好吧
Okay.
我要去后院
I'll be out back.
我要找棵树砍掉
I'm going to find
a tree to chop down.
我懂你的感受，苏西亲
I do know what
you're feeling, Suzy-bean.
有时候我自己也会问，我在这干什么？
I've had moments
myself where I say, "What am I doing here?
谁做的决定？
"Who made this decision?
我怎么可能允许自己做出这种傻事？
"How could I allow myself
to do something so stupid?
为什么它还会发生？
"And why is it
still happening?"
我们女人更感性
We women are
more emotional...
我恨你
I hate you.
不要说恨
Don't say "hate."
为什么？我是说真的
Why not? I mean it.
你现在觉得自己说真的，你是在伤害我
You think you mean it,
in this moment. You're trying to hurt me.
就是这样
Exactly.
我知道你和那个可悲的傻警察干了什么
I know what you do
with that sad, dumb policeman.
他不傻
He's not dumb.
但是我觉得他有点悲哀
But I guess
he is kind of sad.
不管怎样我们不该讨论这事
Anyway,
we shouldn't discuss that.
我连承认我刚刚说过的话
It's not appropriate
for me to even acknowledge
都不可以
what I already just said.
可怜的苏西
Poor Suzy.
为什么生活对你来说这么难呢？
Why is everything
so hard for you?
我们恋爱了。我们只是想在一起，有什么错？
We're in love. We just want to be
together. What's wrong with that?
哦我的天！我们要怎么把这些鱼钩拿出来？
Oh, my God! How are we going to
get these fish hooks out?
我承认我们知道我们惹麻烦了。这是真的
I admit we knew
we'd get in trouble. That part's true.
我知道大家会着急的，我们还是私奔了
We knew people would be
worried, and we still ran away, anyway.
但有些事情发生了，我们不是故意的
But something also happened,
which we didn't do on purpose.
当我们第一次遇见的时候就擦出火花了
When we first met each other,
something happened to us.
你真会说话
That's very eloquent.
你说什么我都无言以对
I can't argue against
anything you're saying.
但是，我没必要反驳。因为你只有12岁
But then again,
I don't have to, 'cause you're 12 years old.
你看，面对现实
Look, let's face it.
你应该比我聪明得多
You're probably a much more
intelligent person than I am.
实际上，我承认
In fact,
I guarantee it.
但聪明的孩子
But even smart kids
stick their finger
有时候也会触电
in electrical
sockets sometimes.
懂事是需要时间的
It takes time to
figure things out.
历史已经证明了这一点。所有人都会犯错误的
It's been proven by history.
All mankind makes mistakes.
保护你不做危险行为
It's our job to
try to protect you
是我们的责任，如果我们做得到的话
from making the
dangerous ones, if we can.
想来一杯吗？
You want a slug?
你急什么？
What's your rush?
你的人生还长着呢
You've got your whole life
in front of yourself.
长着呢
Ahead of you, I mean.
也许吧。再怎么说。你就是个单身汉
Maybe so.
Anyway, you're a bachelor.
你也是
So are you.
对
That's true.
你爱过别人吗？
Did you love someone ever?
有
Yes, I did.
发生什么了？
What happened?
她不爱我
She didn't love me back.
啊
Ah.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry for your loss.
你就该这么说
Anyway, that's what
you're supposed to say.
童子军长日志 9月4日
Scout Master's log.
September 4th.
我听说他要去少管所
I heard he's going
to reform school.
我听说他们要拿掉他大脑的一部分
I heard that they're
going to take out a piece of his brain,
然后把他送去疯人院
send him to
an insane asylum.
我喜欢他女朋友
I like his girl.
我觉得她太邋遢了
She's too scruffy for me.
你说，他们上到三垒了吧
Supposedly,
they got to third base.
没有。他只是搂着她
That's not true.
He just felt her up.
隔着衣服还是没隔衣服？
Over shirt or under shirt?
得了吧
Damn us.
不管我们的事
It's none of our business.
我们这个军队对萨姆 沙考斯基这个伙伴太烂了
This troop has been
very shabby to Field Mate Sam Shakusky.
实际上我们就是一帮刻薄的混蛋
In fact, we've been
a bunch of mean jerks.
他为什么这么不受欢迎？
Why's he so unpopular?
我承认他情绪紊乱
I admit, supposedly,
he's emotionally disturbed,
但他也是个可怜的孤儿。你会作何感想？
but he's also
a disadvantaged orphan. How would you feel?
Nickleby？
Nickleby?
Deluca？
Deluca?
瞌睡虫？
Lazy-Eye?
Gadge？
Gadge?
他是个童子军，他需要我们的帮助
He's a fellow Khaki Scout,
and he needs our help.
我们够不够男人来帮他
Are we man enough
to give that
这样他就不用开脑子了？
so part of his brain
doesn't get removed out of him?
我们是准备好为彼此牺牲的
They were prepared
to die for each other out there.
好吧，好吧
你要怎样？
Okay. Okay.
What do you need?
对初学者？
三码铁丝网
For starters?
Three yards of chicken wire,
一些碎报纸，一桶浆糊
some ripped up newspapers,
and a bucket of wheat paste.
换句话说，完了
In other words, it's over.
我觉得是。现在来说
I guess so.
For the moment.
等另行通知
Until further notice.
对
That's right.
我明白
I understand.
我需要做更好，为了大家
I have to do better,
for everybody.
除了我
Except me.
除了你
Except you.
我希望你可以。我觉得你能做到
Well, I hope you can.
I think you will.
你做得对
You're doing
the right thing.
谁知道会发生什么呢，Duffy
Who knows what's
going to happen, Duffy?
很可能明天还会见到
I'll probably
see you tomorrow.
滚出我家烟囱
Get out of my chimney.
听我说
Listen to me.
我们很友好
我们是来把你带下这座岛的
We're here for friendship.
We're going to get you off this island.
不用，谢谢
No, thanks.
用，谢谢
这是紧急救援
Yes, thanks.
This is an emergency rescue.
对我没意义。我不能没有苏西
It's worthless to me.
There's no point, not without Suzy.
你们怎么过来的？
How'd you get here?
他们把我顺着洗衣槽滑下去
They snuck me down
the laundry chute
在我床上放了个纸人假装是我
and left a papier-mache
dummy in my bed.
嗯……转移策略。聪明。
Hmm... Diversion tactics.
Good thinking.
我们要去哪？
Where we going?
黎巴嫩堡
Fort Lebanon.
我表哥本为叛乱管理着供给前哨
My cousin Ben runs the Supply and
Resources outpost for the Hullabaloo.
他是鹰级童子军，是哨兵。他会知道该怎么做的
He's a Falcon Scout,
Legionnaire. Cousin Ben'll know what to do.
我们能相信他吗？
Can we trust him?
正常情况下，我觉得不能
Normally, I'd say no.
你给莱昂内尔留字条了吗？
Did you leave
another note for Lionel?
这回不行。他从来管不住自己的嘴
Not this time.
He can't keep his trap shut.
而且，我很有可能再也见不到他了
Besides, I'll probably
never see him again.
对
True.
这是圣杰克伍德的岛
This is the island
of St. Jack Wood,
从大陆的尽头向北延伸
extending far north
from Land's End
沿着深峡直到断岩
along the deep water channel
that leads to Broken Rock.
低平的河滩把海岸和小镇分开
A low flood plain
separates the beach from the township above.
那是个小而繁华的居住区
A small but
prosperous community.
气压计的度数是28寸，还在下降
The barometer reads
28 inches and dropping.
强风，你看，已经达到了22里每时
Strong winds, as you can see,
already at 22 knots.
现在是凌晨4:35
The time is now 4:35 a.m.
你对Peabody对Henderson案提起延期审理了吗？
Did you file the motion
of continuance? Peabody v. Henderson?
确认了
It was sustained.
很好
Good.
法官考虑你对宽大处理的申请了吗？
Did the judge consider
your application for leniency?
Rogers对Yentob案的？
Rogers v. Yentob?
- 他同意了
- 太好了
- He granted it.
- Great.
对不起，沃特
I'm sorry, Walt.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你具体是在对什么伤害道歉？
Which injuries
are you apologizing for, specifically?
具体？
Specifically?
只要还痛苦的
Whichever ones still hurt.
这些有一半都是自己造成的
Half of those
were self-inflicted.
我真希望房顶飞出去，我被吸进太空里
I hope the roof flies off,
and I get sucked up into space.
没有我你会过得更好
You'll be better
off without me.
不要为自己感到遗憾了
Stop feeling
sorry for yourself.
为什么
Why?
我们只有自己，沃特
We're all
they've got, Walt.
那不够
That's not enough.
但我不会走的，巴纳比杰克说
"'But I'm not going,'
said Barnaby Jack.
我今晚就逃跑
"'I'm running away
tonight for good.
这一回我不会再被抓到
"'And this time I
won't get caught.'
安娜贝尔低声说，我和你走
"Annabelle whispered,
'I'm coming with you.'
她黄色的头发，根部显出棕色
"Her yellow hair,
now brown at the roots,
在风中飘舞
"caught up in
the wind and danced.
巴纳比杰克拉着安娜贝尔的手
"Barnaby Jack
took Annabelle's hand
把一个糖豆大小的东西摁进她手里
"and pressed something into it
the size of a jellybean.
藏到你袜子里，半夜准备好
"'Hide this in your socks,
and be ready at midnight."'
继续
Continue.
Keep going.
- 继续啊
- 接着念
- Keep going.
- Go on.
- 我们在听
- 很好
- We're listening.
- That's good.
他跳出窗，落在新落的雪地上
"He leapt out the window
and landed in the fresh fallen snow."
我的唱机呢？
Where's my record player?
你不会相信的，先生
You're not going to
believe this one, sir.
新潘赞斯岛的童子军长的整个队都丢了
That Scout Master on
New Penzance has now lost his entire troop.
奇了怪了！
Well, I'll be damned!
这人是谁？
Who is this bimbo?
不知道，先生
Couldn't say, sir.
马上就回
Be right back.
零食帐篷后面有个口香糖机坏了
There's a broken
gumball machine right behind the snack tent.
我不管他们怎么做，你从哪来
I don't care how they do it
where you come from.
你想要汽水？想要糖？想要蛇咬急救箱？
You want pop? You want candy?
You want a snake bite kit?
拿钱来
Get some money.
本表哥？
Cousin Ben?
五分钟之后回来
Come back in five minutes.
那是他吗？
Is this him?
55营的萨姆 沙考斯基 辞职了
Field Mate Sam Shakusky,
Troop 55, resigned.
他很火，太火了
罐子里是什么？
He's hot. Almost too hot.
What's in the can?
76美元，但都是五分的
$76, but it's mostly
in nickels.
给我
Give it to me.
- 你有海军勋章？
- 是的，先生
- Your badge in seamanship?
- Yes, sir.
很好 断岩下面绑着一条冷水捕蟹船
Good. There's a cold water
crabber moored off Broken Rock.
船长还欠我一张欠条
The skipper owes me an IOU.
看看他能不能带上你就当砸蟹爪的
We'll see if he
can take you on as a claw cracker.
会很难，但总比休克疗法好
It won't be an easy life,
but it's better than shock therapy.
谢谢，先生
Thank you, sir.
还有，教堂帐篷呢？
By the way,
where's the chapel tent?
在那，但是神父在家生气呢
Back there,
but the padre's home with the mumps.
为什么问这个？
Why do you ask?
我想带上我妻子
I want to bring my wife.
但我们还没结婚
But we're not married yet.
你是他女朋友？
You his girl?
对
Yeah.
实际上，我是个民事公证人
Technically,
I'm a civil law scrivener.
我有权公证出生，死亡和婚姻
I'm authorized
to declare births, deaths, and marriages.
你们俩小了点。有许可证吗？
You're kind of young.
You got a license?
- 没有
- No.
那我不能让你们合法结合
I can't offer you
a legally binding union.
在州里县里都不合法
It won't hold up in
the state, the county,
或者，说真的，这世界上所有法庭都不承认
or, frankly,
any courtroom in the world
因为你们太年轻，没有许可证明
due to your age,
lack of a license,
父母也不同意
and failure to get
parental consent.
但这个仪式在你们心中
But the ritual does
carry a very important
有很重要的意义
moral weight
within yourselves.
你们不能草率了事。看着我的眼睛
You can't enter
into this lightly. Look into my eyes.
- 你们相爱吗？
- 是
- Do you love each other?
- Yes, we do.
但是考虑一下我说的话
But think about
what I'm saying.
你们确定你们准备好了吗？
Are you sure
you're ready for this?
- 准备好了
- 你们没在听我说话
- Yes, we are.
- They're not listening to me.
- 让我重复一遍
- 我们很着急
- Let me rephrase it.
- We're in a hurry.
你还在嚼……
Are you chewing...
把口香糖吐了，小妹
实际上，每个人
Spit out the gum, sister.
In fact, everybody.
我不喜欢这草率态度
I donˇt like
the snappy attitude.
这是你们人生中最重要的决定
This is the most
important decision you've made in your lives.
在你们草率决定之前
Go over by that trampoline
and talk it through
去那个蹦床那边商量一下
before you give me
another quick answer.
我们确定了
We're sure.
好吧 我们做个血检
Okay. Let's do a blood test.
在上帝的注视下
Under the eye of God,
在本区法律的管辖下
and within the boundaries of
this local jurisdiction,
我们在此举行这个神圣的仪式，在今天，1965年9月5日
which we hereby consecrate on this
day, the 5th of September, 1965.
这个简短的仪式到此结束
That's the end
of the short form.
见证人有异议吗？
Do any of the witnesses
have objections or remarks?
他们一般没有。Scotak？
Usually they don't. Skotak?
我们能把这些五分钱借给他们吗？我担心他们的未来
Can we loan them the nickels?
I'm worried about their future.
那是我的钱
That's my fee.
- 你怎么想？
- 不知道
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
我说什么了？那是我的钱。我要存着这些五分钱
What'd I just say?
That's my fee. I'm keeping the nickels.
好吧，他们可以拿走网球罐
Okay, they can have
the tennis ball can.
在这签名，签首字母缩写，这，还有这
Sign here,
initial here and here.
拿着副本，圣经留下，走吧
Take the carbon,
leave the Bible. Let's go.
他们又要去哪？
Where are they going, again?
如果我没记错的话，他要去捕虾船上工作了
He's going to
work on a shrimper, if I understand correctly.
- 祝他们好
- 我也是
- I wish them well.
- Me, too.
我也是
Me, too.
我觉得他们会回来的
I think they're coming back.
- 快点，水手
- 怎么了？
- Be quick, sailor!
- What happened?
她把她的望远镜落在教堂帐篷的钩子上了
She left her
binoculars on a hook in the chapel tent.
就扔在那吧
Just leave them.
不行 那是她的特异功能！
We can't.
It's her magic power!
顺便说，你杀了你的狗
You killed your dog,
by the way.
- 史努比？
- 嗯哼
- Snoopy?
- Mmm-hmm.
嗯，没办法
Well, it couldn't be helped.
为什么把我当成敌人？
Why do you
consider me your enemy?
因为你女朋友用左撇子剪刀
Because your
girlfriend stabbed me
捅我的背
in the back with
lefty scissors.
她现在是我妻子了
She's my wife now.
祝贺你们
Congratulations.
谢谢，但我是说在那之前，六周前，从一开始
Thank you, but I'm saying before
that, six weeks ago, from day one.
你为什么不喜欢我？
Why don't you like me?
我为什么要喜欢你？没人喜欢你
Why should I?
Nobody else does.
天！他在这！那个逃跑的！停下！
My God! He's here!
The fugitive! Stop him!
阻止他！
Stop him!
在这时候，我不会再反抗了，永远不会
On this spot,
I'll fight no more, forever.
来抓我啊你们这群混蛋
Come and get me,
you bastards!
我没事
I'm okay.
跟着我
Follow me.
走吧，同志们
Company, let's go!
夏普警长，我们找到了失踪的队员
Captain Sharp,
we've located the missing troop.
他们从营地逃走了，我们正在追
They just fled camp.
We're in pursuit.
还有一个12岁的女孩
They're accompanied
by a 12-year-old girl
穿着及膝袜和周末学校的鞋
in knee socks
and Sunday school shoes.
准备，皮尔斯指挥官
Stand by,
Commander Pierce.
杰德，改道去圣杰克伍德
Jed, re-route to
St. Jack Wood.
告诉社会服务部，那男孩在黎巴嫩堡
Tell Social Services
the boy's at Fort Lebanon.
收到 遵命
Roger that.
Will comply.
告诉毕肖普家，苏西在那
Notify the Bishops,
Suzy's there.
兰迪，你能听到他们吗
Randy, you monitoring?
是的 我在路上
Affirmative.
I'm on my way.
喂？
Hello?
喂，毕肖普先生？
Hello, Mr. Bishop?
哦，天 叫上孩子们
Oh, dear God.
Get the boys!
走！快！
Let's go! Right now!
塔控制台 我是杰德
Tower control,
this is Jed.
确认新终点坐标，a 2 2 7 1 5
Confirm coordinates for new
destination, Alpha two-two-seven-one-fiver.
上面阴云密布
Looking pretty soupy up here.
在暴风雨到来之前不会安定下来
Wouldn't mind setting down
before the pot boils over.
社会服务部，扶稳了
Hang on, Social Services.
再说一遍，暴风雨已经冲破了
Once again, storm
waters have just breached
Black Beacon水库大坝
the dam at
Black Beacon Reservoir.
洪水预警开始生效 采取紧急预防措施
A flash flood
alert is in effect. Take immediate precautions
暴风雨向咱们刮过来了
That's coming our way.
找到他们了吗？
Did you find them?
准备移动到高地
Prepare to mobilize
to higher ground.
圣杰克教堂是预定的躲避风暴的地方
St. Jack's Church
is the designated storm shelter.
叫所有童子军到我帐篷外面集合，跑步前进
Notify all Scouts to
muster outside my tent, on the double.
注意了，同志们！
Attention, company!
准备好
Prepare for...
那是谁？
Who's that?
你说你是童子军？
You call yourself
a Khaki Scout?
抱歉，先生？
Sorry, sir?
你他妈是哪个营的啊，你个混蛋？
Where's your goddamn troop,
you son of a bitch?
你没找到他们？
You don't have them?
他们会死的！
They could get
killed out there!
我要当场拆掉你的指挥权
I'm field stripping
you of your command.
注意了，同志们！
Attention, company!
准备紧急撤离！
Prepare for
emergency evacuation!
先生，带药了吗？
Sir, do you have
your medicine?
我马上就回
I'll be right back.
站住别动！
Hold your positions!
军营秘书，报告现状
Company secretary,
status report.
都到齐了，童子军长
All accounted for,
Scout Master!
好了孩子们，我们准备逃了，集合！
Okay, boys,
we're going to make a run for it! Fall in!
走吧！
Let's move!
快，跟着我！
Come on, follow me!
谁是管事的？
Who's in charge here?
兰迪，怎么了？
Randy, what happened?
让指挥官下来！
Take the commander off me!
苏西？
Suzy?
苏西？萨姆？
Suzy? Sam?
他们又逃跑了。
They ran away again.
我们需要回去，我需要志愿者
We got to go back out there.
I need volunteers.
你，你，还有你
You, and you and you.
- 你？
- 你可以吗？
- You?
- Are you all right?
当然
Of course I am.
那孩子呢？
Where's the boy?
我们还不知道
We don't know yet.
不接受你这个回答
That's not acceptable.
那你想让我说什么，女士？
What do you
want me to say, lady?
给杰德倒杯咖啡
Somebody get
Jed a cup of coffee.
- 你是夏普警长
- 对
- You're Captain Sharp.
- That's correct.
我是社会服务部的，我遣送这孩子让您个人监护
I'm Social Services. I remanded the
boy into your personal custody.
你对他的安全负有责任
You're responsible
for his safety.
我听说他刚被闪电击中
I'm told that
he's just been struck by lightning.
我是第一次听说这种事
That's the first
I've heard of it.
是真的
It's true.
你就是童子军长沃德吧
Scout Master Ward,
I presume.
是的，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
你赶不上你的名声好啊
Your reputation
precedes you.
你们两个是最骇人听闻地
You two are
the most appallingly
不负责任的监护人
incompetent
custodial guardians
27年来社会服务部
Social Services has
ever had the misfortune
还从来没遇见过你俩这样的！
to encounter in
a 27-year career!
你们还有什么可说？
What do you have to
say for yourselves?
你们不能这样。他们会把他在那活活吃掉的
You can't do this.
They'll eat him alive in there.
在哪？
Where?
那地方叫什么来着？
What's the name
of the place again?
少管所
Juvenile Refuge.
听着就像监狱
Sounds like jail.
找到那孩子，送到社会服务部
Just find the boy,
and deliver him to Social Services.
你不用做别的了
Nothing else
is in your power.
对不起。我们能回到救援中吗？
I'm sorry.
Can we get back to the rescue now?
- 苏西还在外面
- 你是谁？
- Suzy is still out there.
- Who are you?
沃特和劳拉 毕肖普，他们的女儿就是那个失踪女孩
Walt and Laura Bishop,
their daughter's the missing girl.
那个捅人小孩的父母？
The parents of the stabber?
我反对这个描述。她是先被袭击的
I object to that description.
She was attacked.
什么？
Excuse me?
我需要细节，她捅的那个童子军呢？
I want the details about that.
Where's the Scout she knifed?
就在这
Right here.
- 童子军Redford，先生
- 他情况怎么样？
- Field Mate Redford, sir.
- What's his condition?
他可能患有慢性肾功能不全
He may suffer some limited
chronic kidney insufficiency.
这是诊断报告
Here's the report.
- 没时间看这个了！
- 她说得对
- We don't have time for that!
- She's right.
- 走吧
- 停下！
- Let's go.
- Stop!
没人能出去
Nobody's going anywhere.
他不能被休克疗法
He's not getting
shock therapy.
够了！你这是明知故犯
That's it!
I am citing you for gross misconduct.
你被传唤
You are hereby
summoned to appear...
我也诉你！
I'm writing you up back!
起诉你虐待……
Be notified that
you stand accused of mistreatment...
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
我不会让你这样做的！
I won't let you do it!
看！
Look!
- 他们跑了
- 谁？
- They're gone.
- Who?
- 苏西？
- 萨姆！
- Suzy?
- Sam!
- 他们就在这？
- 是
- They're here?
- Yeah.
他们去哪了？回答我！
Where'd they go?
Answer me!
停！停下！
Halt! Stop!
呆在那别动
Stay there.
等等，拿着
Wait, take these!
你要去哪？你在干嘛？
Where are you going?
What are you doing?
下来！
Come down!
社会服务部。能听见吗？完毕
Social Services,
do you read me? Over.
我们可能得游过去
We might have to
swim for it.
有多深？我没带救生衣
How deep is it?
I didn't bring my life jacket.
我不知道，但如果太浅，我们也会摔断脖子的
I don't know, but if it's too
shallow, we'll break our necks anyway.
抓住我
Hang on to me.
好
Okay.
不，我没结婚，但是我是个警察
No, I'm not married, but I'm a police officer.
申请拒绝 对不起
Application denied.
I'm sorry.
我不允许。完毕
I cannot
authorize that. Over.
律师们，从法律上看怎么办？完毕
Counselors, what's
the legal perspective? Over.
这种情况下我绝对有自信提起诉讼
In this state,
I would litigate with extreme confidence.
- 我同意
- 根据民事条例
- I concur.
- Open with Article 15
第15条
of the Codes of
Civic Jurisdiction.
在任何情况下，无人
No party,
under any circumstances,
在不存在永久持有权的偏见的情况下
shall be denied due
and proper consideration
可以被剥夺应得权利和应有的关心
without prejudice
in perpetuity.
再一次，数到三
On three again.
等等
Wait.
以防万一，万一这成了自杀
Just in case
this is a suicide
或者他们抓住了我们，我们再也见不到对方了
or they capture us
and we never see each other again anymore,
我想谢谢你嫁给我
I just want to say
thank you for marrying me.
我很高兴能认识你，苏西
I'm glad I got
to know you, Suzy.
我感觉你身上还有电呢
I think you've still
got lightning in you.
跳吧
Let's jump.
不！妈的！
No! God damn it!
告诉他。完毕
Tell him. Over.
夏普警长要
Captain Sharp is
offering to assume
承担养父责任
the responsibility
of foster parenthood.
他想要你和他住
He wants you
to live with him.
你愿意接受吗，沙考斯基先生？
Is this acceptable to you, Mr. Shakusky?
怎么样，哥们？
What do you think, pal?
我们要下来了，完毕 结束通话
We're coming down.
Over and out.
他们要下来了  完毕 结……
They're coming down.
Over and...
别放手
Don't let go.
Black Beacon风暴
The Black Beacon
storm was considered
被美国恶劣天气部门认为
by the US Department
of Inclement Weather
是20世纪后半叶该地区遭受的
to be the region's
most destructive meteorological event
毁灭性最强的气象灾害
of the second half
of the 20th century.
它持续了六次涨潮，
It lingered through six high
tides and inundated the islands
以狂风洪水席卷了岛屿
with punishing winds
and extreme high waters.
在圣杰克伍德，巨浪毁坏了商场栈道
On St. Jack Wood,
powerful surges broke the arcade boardwalk
摧毁了村庄的演奏台和赌场
and demolished
the village bandstand and casino.
童子军长日志 10月10日
Scout Master's log.
October 10th.
重建工作在比预计速度快得多地继续
Reconstruction continues
increasingly ahead of schedule,
我认为这是因为军队中爆发出的
which I attribute to
a particularly robust
团队精神
esprit de corps
among the troop.
但厕所还是继续……
The latrine, however,
does continue to present...
对不起，先生？
Excuse me, sir?
- 你有新兵了？
- 是的，先生
- You've got the new recruit?
- Yes, sir.
- 他什么军衔？
- 他没有
- What's his rank?
- He doesn't have one.
鸽级童子军。我们给他补上
Pigeon Scout.
Let's get him a patch.
新潘赞斯的海岸地区
The coastal
areas of New Penzance
被永久损毁了
were battered
and changed forever.
高度
Height.
63寸
63 inches.
3.25英里潮汐湾被从地图上抹去
Mile 3.25
Tidal Inlet was erased from the map.
但接下来的秋天的收获
But harvest yields
the following autumn
远远超过了之前的记录
far exceeded any
previously recorded,
庄稼的质量也格外的好
and the quality of the crops
was said to be extraordinary.
所以你看，作曲家Benjamin Britten
So you see,
the composer Benjamin Britten
分开了整个乐团
has taken the whole
orchestra apart.
现在他把他们重新集合在一支赋格曲里
Now he puts it
back together again in a fugue.
乐器一个接一个加入进来
The instruments come
in one after another
和原来的顺序一样
从短笛开始
in the same order as before,
beginning with the piccolo.
而结束的时候，在所有乐器都加入……
And at the end, when all the
instruments have finally come in...
苏西，莱昂内尔，莫瑞，鲁迪，吃完饭啦！
Suzy, Lionel,
Murray, Rudy, dinner!
……旋律中时，当其他乐器
...melody, while
the other instruments...
叫你们最后一遍！
Don't make us
ask twice!
明天见
See you tomorrow.
谢谢观赏
翻译：猫猫@豆瓣
别走开！后面还有！要一直看到最后哟！
现在我们要说明
Now we will
demonstrate the orchestration
德普拉（配乐）的音乐套曲的编曲
of Monsieur Desplat's
musical suite.
电子节拍器来设定时间
A little electronic
metronome sets the time.
首先是竖琴
First, a harp.
接下来，拨奏大提琴
Next, pizzicato cellos.
长笛和短笛
Flute and piccolo.
电吉他
Electric guitar.
四弦吉他
Ukulele.
古典吉他
Classical guitar.
班卓琴
Banjo.
薄木片
Thin wood blocks.
还有两架竖琴
And two more harps.
B-3管风琴
B-3 organ.
钢片琴
Celesta.
颤音琴
Bowed vibraphone.
和钢琴
And piano.
拨奏小提琴
Pizzicato violins.
还有低音提琴
And double bass.
管钟
Tubular bells.
钟琴
And the glockenspiel.
钹
The ride cymbal.
Piatti（这个翻译无能）
Piatti.
小鼓
Snare drums.
Gran casa（这个翻译无能）
Gran casa.
定音鼓
Timpani!
16个男中低音
Sixteen baritone bass singers.
木琴
Xylophone.
巴松管
Bassoons.
单簧管
Clarinet.
法国号
French horns.
次中音萨克斯
Tenor sax.
长号
Trombone.
大号
Tuba!
小号
Trumpets.
三角铁
Triangle.
谢谢欣赏
Thank you very
much for listening.